René Ricardo

Montevideo, Montevideo, Uruguay

renerp2016@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/renericardoperez

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with experience in lots of modern frontend technologies and web tools such as SASS, LESS, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, JSON, Webpack, Rest, Angular, React.js, Redux, Ionic, Pug, and Web markup. As a designer amateur, I love working with drawing and sketch tools like Balsamiq, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, and Adobe Illustrator. My main programming languages are javascript and typescript but I will always be pleased to learn new ones in my next jobs.

I love to support the online community because it is a great way to share my knowledge with others. On my GitHub page, there are some repositories of my personal projects and on my NPM page, there are some of my publications.

I love following design patterns for keeping my code cleaner and readable for any person who wants to continue my work. Also, I like to be part of communicative and hardworking teams where anyone can share his point of view on whatever problem needs a solution.

- ** In my free time, I also love to take shots of landscapes and city views.
- Github: https://github.com/2rhop
- NPM: https://www.npmjs.com/~2rhop
- Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/ricky.trips
- -iStock portfolio: https://www.istockphoto.com/es/portfolio/ReneRicardo

Experience

ct Senior Software Engineer

Clevertech

Feb 2022 - Present (1 year 11 months)

- Develop web apps using React framework
- Release quality code using React Testing Library and Jest
- Create and update CI/CD workflows for enhancing release deployment processes using GitHub Actions

#github #javascript #typescript #git #pipelines #vite #vitest #jest #reacttestinglibrary #redux



Ssr. Adv. Software Engineer

Altimetrik

May 2021 - Feb 2022 (10 months)

- Develop web applications using React, Redux, Typescript
- Release quality code using frameworks like Jest.js, Enzyme and React Testing Library

#reactjs #javascript #typescript #git #webpack #enzyme #jest #reacttestinglibrary #redux

Software Engineer II

Ascentis a UKG Company

Feb 2020 - May 2021 (1 year 4 months)

- Develop web apps using React, Redux, Angular, and other FE technologies
- Release quality code with Jest.js and Enzyme framework
- Learn BE stack technologies such as .NET framework
- Learn how to track user statistics using Matomo.js framework

#reactjs #angular2 #javascript #typescript #git #webpack #enzyme #jest #redux



Frontend Developer (remote)

Informage Studios S.L.U.

Nov 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- Develop Web Apps using javascript frameworks such as Angular & React
- Develop static and dynamic Web Apps from Adobe files (.ai, .psd, .xd)

#reactis #angular2 #javascript #typescript #git #webpack #jest #redux #nextjs #adobe

Software Engineer

Datys

Sep 2017 - Oct 2019 (2 years 2 months)

- Develop Web applications using Angular framework
- Integrate these apps with automated tests using Karma and Jasmine

#angular2 #javascript #typescript #git #webpack #jasmine



Frontend Developer (remote)

Caminalta UG

Jul 2017 - May 2018 (11 months)

- Develop web applications using Angular framework

#angular2 #javascript #typescript #git #webpack

Education



University of Holguín

Ingeniería, Ingeniería informática 2012 - 2017

Instituto Politécnico de Informática de Holguín

Computer Science Technician, Computer Science 2009 - 2012

Licenses & Certifications

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript Landing Page with Modal Forms Udemy UC-0212VQR1
- **OPERIOR OF SECTION APPROACH APP**
- Curso de maquetación web de lo básico a lo avanzado Udemy UC-RREN511B
- g Gymglish Level Certificate (B2~C1) Gymglish
- React Fundamentals Udemy UC-AQS62PXH
- React.js, quick start Udemy UC-J8SW4V9V
- React in 1 Hour Learn the Fundamentals, Fast Udemy UC-LQQFRU2G
- (A) Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Curso de Introduccion al Desarrollo Web: HTML y CSS (I) Google Actívate 74FKEXW8G
- Curador de datos Fundación Carlos Slim ol1 hi5334
- **Desarrollador Front-end** Fundación Carlos Slim q9i0kjo32
- (A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- **EF SET English Certificate (C1 Advanced)** EF Standard English Test (EF SET) cert/AhfzQQ
- Curso de Introduccion al Desarrollo Web: HTML y CSS (II) Google Actívate

Web Design for Web Developers - Udemy

UC-a5aaa55f-2dc3-4608-8eed-b56ec01f33a9

Mobile App Design: From Sketches to Interactive Prototypes - Udemy

UC-a73eb43c-6b54-4a88-86ee-a9a2858b6141

Adobe illustrator For UI / UX Design - Udemy

UC-e6804dc3-65ce-4b50-94f0-0cdb720262c3

- Fundamentos de Kanban para desarrollo de software LinkedIn AbCWB3I_fQjsxWO_EBOB0rlMrb5A
- in CSS con SASS esencial LinkedIn
- React y Polymer: Desarrollo de aplicación web progresiva LinkedIn
- Yue práctico: Desarrollo de interfaz web para gestión deportiva LinkedIn
- REACT práctico: Interfaz para aplicación web de gestión deportiva LinkedIn
- in Learning Redux LinkedIn
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4 Coursera N95HKAM6GQKB
- in Critical Thinking LinkedIn
- Problem Solving (Basic) Certificate HackerRank 3419f1ab61da
- JavaScript (Basic) Certificate HackerRank 6260a6bde638
- CSS Certificate HackerRank
 0d041e47d3b9
- React (Basic) Certificate HackerRank

99ea3b4d4277

- in JavaScript: Patterns LinkedIn
- in Building a Resilient Web LinkedIn
- in Learning RxJS LinkedIn
- in Node.js Essential Training LinkedIn
- Testing React with Jest and Testing Library Udemy UC-ae27d9f0-395c-42a1-a2dd-ca8a6e98b81a
- in JavaScript Code Challenges LinkedIn
- in Get Ready for Generative AI LinkedIn
- in Learning Apollo LinkedIn
- User Experience (UX) EducacionIT 94030868628

Skills

Resolución de problemas • React.js • Angular • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Desarrollo web • Web Design • Desarrollo de software • Programación • Web Applications • Application Development

Honors & Awards

Finalist on ACM/ICPC Programming Contest at UHO, Cuba - ACM/ICPC 2014